<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-05T21:30:09+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Happy Housing Blog</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><author><name>Happy Housing Limited</name></author><entry><title type="html">Tips for Screening Tenants</title><link href="/post/tips-for-screening-tenants" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tips for Screening Tenants" /><published>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/post/tips-for-screening-tenants</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/tips-for-screening-tenants"><![CDATA[<p><strong>What is tenant screening and why does it matter?</strong></p>

<p>The overall process of screening a tenant can be very short but it is the most important step to take before signing the lease.</p>

<p>Any prospective tenant will behave as the ideal candidate for your property when applying, and this can make it difficult to make the final decision. However, with a screen process, it is easy to eliminate the candidates who do not fit your criteria. During this process, you will get to know your tenant by gathering information.</p>

<p>Finding good, trustworthy, reliable tenants will ensure that your property is respected, rent is paid on time and there are no disturbances, complaints or damage to the neighbourhood/apartment block.</p>

<p>Firstly, you should have an idea of the “ideal” candidate. Create criteria that you wish to follow for yourself during the process. Try to keep this practical, for example you know you have a small apartment, with four chairs as the dining table, ideally you would like to fit a maximum of 4 people into your property, so a family of 6 people would be too large.</p>

<p><strong>Gather personal information about the tenant/tenant group</strong></p>

<p>Find out why they are applying: on the application form, make sure to ask why the tenant/tenant group are applying for your property. This will give you a brief idea of who they are, and will start the process of vetting them.</p>

<p>Proof of identity:</p>
<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Photo ID: your candidates should show you proof of identity. It’s okay to accept a photocopy initially but it may be ideal to ask them to bring along proof of identity to the interview/viewing later on in the process.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Utility Bill: request a utility bill as proof of the candidates current address or previous address. This will help verify a previous landlord reference. This may also show the tenant is able to manage their bills effectively.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Money Management: Ask for bank statements. Generally you would request 3 months back.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>References:
Current Employer: Ask the tenant for a reference from their current employer. Look up the company online first and call the number given on their website/social media. Ask for the HR department and enquire about the ‘employee’ before asking to speak with whomever gave the reference. Check how long the employee has been working at the company and if they are on a full time, part time or fixed term contract.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Previous Landlord: ask for a written reference from the previous landlord that contains a name, address and contact number. Always contact the previous landlord and make sure to ask them the full address of the property. It may seem obvious, but it’s important to confirm the address matches the utility bill you have been provided. Previous landlord references are known to be commonly forged.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>In your conversation with the previous landlord, ask them about the tenant character, check if the tenant gave the correct notice period and if they provided any reason for leaving the property. You can compare their response with the explanation provided by the tenant.</p>

<p>Ask if the tenant reported issues/repair requests promptly, and if the tenant allowed access to have repairs carried out.</p>

<p>Find out if they had any issues with the tenant: were they difficult to deal with, communicate with, were they demanding. Check if the tenant got their deposit back when evacuating from the property.</p>

<p>All of these questions will make it clear if the tenant/tenant group does not fit the ‘ideal’ candidate for your property.</p>

<p><strong>Schedule an interview/viewing</strong></p>

<p>Hosting a viewing of your property is a great way to invite prospective tenants to the property to take a look, ask questions and meet the letting agent/landlord they will be dealing with if their application gets accepted. However, it is a great way for you to get to know the candidates.</p>

<p>An open house can be convenient to allow a large range of prospective tenants to see the property at once, but it is important to schedule an individual viewing for the tenant/tenant group so you can get the opportunity to speak with them and ask questions. You will also get an idea of their character and willingness to communicate with you. This will benefit you later when they request repairs/report problems and need assistance.</p>

<p>Ask questions: Use the opportunity to talk to your prospective tenant, as sort of an informal interview. Find out why they have chosen to move from their current accommodation, instead of renewing their lease. You can mention how much the deposit and first month rent will cost and check if they will be capable of paying this. Ask if they had any issue with their previous landlord or property, or simply ask for feedback on what they may have been missing in their previous accommodation.</p>

<p>These questions may have been covered already in the information gathering stage, however asking these questions in person may open up a discussion and allow the tenant to provide information you have not yet learned, give you more information on a topic you wish to know more about or verify information provided by the previous landlord.</p>

<p><strong>Trust your instincts</strong></p>

<p>Note the candidate ‘manner’ during the overall process. Whether you’re communicating over the phone, email, instant message, or in person, notice how they respond to you and interact with you. Are they vague, demanding, rushed, or otherwise, these may be telltale signs the candidate will have difficulty interacting with you later on.</p>

<p>There are a number of things you cannot ask during the application process, such as if they have any arrests or convictions, so it is important to know if the individual or group you are accepting into your property is going to be troublesome for the property or the neighbours.</p>

<p><strong>Lease Agreement</strong></p>

<p>It is recommended that you have a lease agreement in place with your tenants. This will enable you to set out your expectations for the tenant/tenant group during their tenancy. It will also allow you to add clauses under the “Special Conditions” section, i.e. no smoking, no pets.</p>

<p>It is recommended to keep an inventory of your property, and take pictures before the tenant moves in.</p>

<p>Make sure the lease agreement complies with the Residential Tenancies Act 2004.</p>

<p>Finally, we recommend that you double-check your best candidates. HappyHousing will enable you to cover the full process so you cover all the bases before accepting an application. In the meantime, you are aware of the most effective ways to make sure you are accepting the most suitable candidates for your property so go and find your ideal tenant.</p>]]></content><author><name>Joanne Heraghty</name></author><category term="Guide" /><category term="Information" /><category term="screening" /><category term="landlord" /><category term="tenants" /><category term="applications" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is tenant screening and why does it matter?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">All about Viewings</title><link href="/post/all-about-viewings" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="All about Viewings" /><published>2021-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/post/all-about-viewings</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/all-about-viewings"><![CDATA[<p><em>Coming soon…</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Joanne Heraghty</name></author><category term="Guide" /><category term="Information" /><category term="renters" /><category term="information" /><category term="2021" /><category term="viewings" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coming soon…]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Renting in Ireland in 2021</title><link href="/post/renting-in-2021" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Renting in Ireland in 2021" /><published>2021-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/post/renting-in-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/renting-in-2021"><![CDATA[<p>We have created a helpful guide to renting a property in Ireland in 2021.</p>

<p><strong>#1 Be a persistent searcher.</strong> Over at Happy Housing, we like to call those of you who sift endlessly through the property listings as searchers.</p>

<p>As the housing crisis hangs over us all, finding a rental property in Ireland is becoming increasingly difficult for searchers. You need to be persistently scrolling through listings, monitoring and tracking properties in the location you are interested in renting in.</p>

<p><strong>#2 Move quickly.</strong> Hesitating could lose you your spot. Once your application has been reviewed and the landlord or agency is ready to move to the next stage, act as quickly as possible to secure your place.</p>

<p><strong>#3 Go to viewings.</strong> If the opportunity comes up to view an available property, go to the viewing and check it out. While the advertisement might include photos of the property, it is always a good idea to check it out and get a feel for the place. Read <a href="https://blog.happyhousing.ie/post/all-about-viewings">All about Viewings</a> for a useful guide on viewings.</p>

<p><strong>#4 Perseverance is key.</strong> Things don’t always go as planned. Sometimes properties fall through, viewings get cancelled, and you are likely to be rejected. But try to stay positive, these things take time.</p>

<p><strong>#5 Be ready!</strong> Your application can be accepted at any time to progress to the next stage of the process, so it is important to be readily prepared with everything they ask for from you.</p>

<p>The landlord or property manager might ask you for the below:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Reference from your current employer</li>
  <li>References from your current landlord</li>
  <li>Current and previous addresses</li>
  <li>Bank statements</li>
  <li>Photo ID (Passport, driver’s license, etc.)</li>
  <li>PPS number</li>
  <li>First month’s rent and one month deposit</li>
</ul>

<p>In some instances, they might ask you some questions as to why you are looking for a new place to live.</p>

<p><strong>#6 Keep an open mind.</strong> You might have an idea of your dream place but don’t be hasty to rule out properties that come up. Look at the pictures, go to the viewing, ask relevant questions and maybe take a day to explore the area.</p>

<p><strong>#7 Manage your expectations.</strong> There are many factors to consider when you’re looking for a new place: rent costs, location, transport system/parking, space, furnishings etc., so it’s important you prioritise what factor is most important for you.</p>

<p><strong>#8 Realistic budgeting.</strong> Whether it’s your first time renting or you have been renting for 10 years, budgeting is key. Make sure you have properly thought everything out before signing the lease. You should account for the cost of rent, electricity, bin collection, wifi, insurance, groceries, your personal subscriptions and anything else you might pay for on a weekly/bi-weekly or monthly basis.</p>

<p>Be mindful, you also need to pay for a TV license, even if you don’t own a TV. This is an annual, one-off fee of €160 which is paid by the occupant of the property, not the owner.</p>

<p>Please see the <a href="https://www.tvlicence.ie/home/tv-licence-home.html">TV license website</a> for more information.</p>

<p><strong>#9 Read and re-read the lease agreement.</strong> The lease is a legally binding document and should be read before signing at least twice. Make sure all of your questions or concerns are addressed.</p>

<p><strong>#10 Make sure the property is registered with the Residential Tenancy Board (RTB).</strong> The RTB is in place to regulate and support the housing rental sector and ensure that landlords and tenants are aware of their rights and responsibilities.</p>

<p>You can check the register anytime on the <a href="https://www.rtb.ie/check/index.html">RTB website</a></p>

<p><strong>#11 Photograph everything.</strong> As soon as you move in, take electricity and gas readings and photograph them for your records. Take photos of the property on your move-in day to document any existing damage in the property and take record of the original state of the property. Share the photographs with your landlord or property manager or date stamp them for your own records.</p>

<p><strong>#12 Get everything in writing.</strong> Document every interaction you have with your landlord or property manager. Keep written records of any issues, arrangements, resolutions etc. discussed, in case you need it in the future.</p>

<p>A lot of the time it is easier to communicate via phone call, in this case, it is no harm to summarise the conversation in a quick email or message to the landlord following the call.</p>

<p><strong>#13 Create an inventory.</strong> Create an inventory of everything that is in the property when you first move in and share this with your landlord or property manager.</p>

<p><strong>#14 Get an energy rating.</strong> Request the BER rating for the property from your landlord or property manager. They are required to present one.</p>

<p><strong>#15 Consider insurance.</strong> You may need content insurance to cover your personal belongings in the house. Check with your landlord or property manager to see if you’re covered under their existing insurance.</p>

<p><strong>#16 Know your rights around rent-raising.</strong> Once you begin your tenancy, your rent cannot be raised for two years.</p>

<p><strong>#17 Get receipts.</strong> Always make sure to get receipts. You are entitled to a receipt within 72 hours of payment.</p>

<p>It is important you receive a receipt when you pay your deposit, in particular. This might get recorded in the Rent Book, if your landlord or property manager keeps one.</p>

<p><strong>#18 Check your notice periods.</strong> Find out how much notice you are entitled to receive if your landlord or property manager wants you to move out, and how much notice you will need to give if you wish to move out.</p>

<p>The notice period is based on how long you have been in the property and should be clarified in the lease agreement.</p>

<p><strong>#19 Moving out.</strong> Once you have signed the lease, you can only move out if the landlord or property manager agrees to terminate the lease agreement early or allow you to find a replacement tenant.</p>

<p>Ending your lease early absolves your legal right to your deposit. It is at the discretion of the landlord or property manager to return the deposit to you.</p>

<p><strong>#20 Living with other people.</strong> Chances are, you will be sharing a property with other people: friends or strangers. There are helpful tools available to assist with splitting bills, sending money easily etc. Look out for handy apps or websites to help.</p>]]></content><author><name>Joanne Heraghty</name></author><category term="Guide" /><category term="Information" /><category term="renters" /><category term="information" /><category term="2021" /><category term="housing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have created a helpful guide to renting a property in Ireland in 2021.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing Happy Housing</title><link href="/post/introducing-happy-housing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Happy Housing" /><published>2021-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/post/introducing-happy-housing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/introducing-happy-housing"><![CDATA[<p>We have all had terrible experiences renting. We started this journey with one objective in mind: <strong>reform housing renting in Ireland</strong>. One year on, we are months away from launching our new housing rental platform, Happy Housing.</p>

<p>Happy Housing is <strong>an all-in-one online platform</strong> for managing the <strong>housing rental process</strong> from start to finish. This results in <strong>less stress</strong>, better <strong>organisation</strong> and clearer <strong>communication</strong> during the application process and the tenancy.</p>

<p>We want to make renting a house as straight-forward as booking a hotel or ordering a takeaway.</p>

<h2 id="applicants">Applicants</h2>

<p>We understand there is no one-size-fits-all filter we all use when scrolling through listings, so we offer a more <strong>advanced search</strong> experience for applicants. You will have the option to filter your searches to meet your specific needs. For example, you may search for an <em>apartment</em> that <em>allows smokers</em>, <em>allows pets</em> and has <em>on-street parking</em>.</p>

<p>Our goal is to provide you with a start-to-finish application journey. Not only will Happy Housing serve as tool for searching for properties, but you will also have the ability to save <strong>customised searches</strong>, and receive <strong>notifications</strong> once properties matching your search become available. Additionally, if the property owner has enabled it, you will have the option to <strong>submit an application</strong> via Happy Housing where you can collate all your information in one place and submit it once your initial application has been accepted. And finally (we left the best part for last), you will hear back. <strong>Yes - whether you have been rejected or accepted, you will receive a response.</strong></p>

<h2 id="landlords">Landlords</h2>

<p>Unlike the current rental platforms available in Ireland we, not only provide a <strong>solution to advertising your property online</strong> but, provide a space where you can receive and view all your applications in one place, <strong>interact with your applicants</strong> and <strong>manage the tenancy</strong> once the lease is signed.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-the-benefits-of-considering-happy-housing">What are the benefits of considering Happy Housing?</h3>
<ul>
  <li>We guarantee to save you time and effort.</li>
  <li>You will be able to <strong>view and manage all your applications</strong> in one place.</li>
  <li>You will no longer need to include your personal phone number or email address on your ads, if you choose not to.</li>
  <li>You will have a <strong>centralised place to organise and manage all your information</strong>.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="how-do-we-do-all-this">How do we do all this?</h3>
<p>When you sign up to Happy Housing you will have a <strong>dedicated dashboard</strong> that will contain the <strong>tenant management tool</strong>, <strong>applications</strong> section, <strong>property management page</strong>, <strong>chat</strong> function and your own profile.</p>

<h2 id="tenants">Tenants</h2>

<p>You become a ‘tenant’ once you have signed the lease. 
You may have a pre-existing account with Happy Housing from your application stage – or you may have joined the site at your landlord’s request. Whatever the reason, you will have an account on the site where you can <strong>organise all of your information in one place</strong>.</p>
<h3 id="what-we-can-do-for-you">What we can do for you!</h3>
<ul>
  <li>You will have a <strong>dedicated space</strong> to organise all your documents and files.</li>
  <li>You will have more <strong>open communication with your landlord</strong> to receive the support you need during your tenancy.</li>
  <li>Once your current tenancy is finished, you will have all your information in one place, ready to start the application process all over again.</li>
  <li>…and much more.</li>
</ul>

<p><em>The future of renting is coming…</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Joanne Heraghty</name></author><category term="News" /><category term="Announcements" /><category term="business" /><category term="new" /><category term="hello" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have all had terrible experiences renting. We started this journey with one objective in mind: reform housing renting in Ireland. One year on, we are months away from launching our new housing rental platform, Happy Housing.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Working with Enums in Angular components</title><link href="/post/working-with-enums-in-angular-components" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Working with Enums in Angular components" /><published>2020-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/post/working-with-enums-in-angular-components</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/working-with-enums-in-angular-components"><![CDATA[<p>This is a short guide on using Enums in an Angular application.
Below you will see how to:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Reference an Enum in your<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">component.html</code> templates</li>
  <li>Itterate over an enum using <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*ngFor</code> and the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">keyvalue</code> pipe</li>
  <li>Conditionally show content using an Enum and<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*ngIf</code></li>
  <li>Get all the values of an enum as an<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Array&lt;sting&gt;</code></li>
</ul>

<h1 id="intro">Intro</h1>
<p><em>You can skip the next block of text if you just want to get the actual details (I respect that)</em></p>

<p>I love using Enums in TypeScript as I am a terrible developer with a terrible memory and let my editor’s auto complete do 80% of my job. Enums let you avoid using strings and having to remember what string values you used. They also allow you to lock down the values a property can be, so that a user can’t just submit any value they want.So if you aren’t using them, start using them, and if you are already using them, use them more, use them to a fault. Be the Enums you want to see in the world.</p>

<h1 id="example-use-of-an-enum-for-those-unfamiliar">Example use of an enum for those unfamiliar</h1>
<div class="language-typescript highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c1">// This is our PropertyType enum</span>
<span class="c1">// We give each value a string value otherwise PropertyType.House would return 0, Property.Apartment would return 1, and so on</span>
<span class="kr">enum</span> <span class="nx">PropertyType</span> <span class="p">{</span>
  <span class="nx">House</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">House</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="nx">Apartment</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">Apartment</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="nx">Flat</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">Flat</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="nx">Studio</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">Studio</span><span class="dl">'</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="c1">// Our class which has a 'type' property.</span>
<span class="c1">// We want to lock type down to a set of predefined values</span>
<span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nx">Property</span> <span class="p">{</span>
  <span class="kd">constructor</span><span class="p">(</span>
    <span class="k">public</span> <span class="nx">monthlyPrice</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kr">number</span><span class="p">,</span>
    <span class="k">public</span> <span class="kd">type</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nx">PropertyType</span>
  <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">}</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="c1">// Creates a property successfully</span>
<span class="kd">const</span> <span class="nx">property</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nx">Property</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1250</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">PropertyType</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Apartment</span><span class="p">);</span>

<span class="c1">// Will display an error from our linter and in the Angular CLI</span>
<span class="kd">const</span> <span class="nx">property</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nx">Property</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1250</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">PropertyType</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">RANDOM_VALUE</span><span class="p">);</span>

</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Enums can be used in your Angular templates.This is handy for situations like avoiding a hard coded set of values for a dropdown menu or displaying different content based on your component state.In my opinion, this pairs very nicely with reactive forms.
To make an Enum accessible in your Angular template you need to first store it in a variable in our component.ts file.For this example, we will create a simple reactive form to create a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Property</code></p>

<div class="language-typescript highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c1">// Declaring our Enum. The Enum could also be imported from another file if needed </span>
<span class="kr">enum</span> <span class="nx">PropertyType</span> <span class="p">{</span>
  <span class="nx">House</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">House</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="nx">Apartment</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">Apartment</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="nx">Flat</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">Flat</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="nx">Studio</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">Studio</span><span class="dl">'</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="p">@</span><span class="nd">Component</span><span class="p">({</span>
  <span class="na">selector</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">app-property-component</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="na">templateUrl</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">./property.component.html</span><span class="dl">'</span>
<span class="p">})</span>
<span class="k">export</span> <span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nx">PropertyComponent</span><span class="p">{</span>

  <span class="c1">// Make a variable reference to our Enum</span>
  <span class="nx">ePropertyType</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">PropertyType</span><span class="p">;</span>

  <span class="c1">// Build our form</span>
  <span class="nl">form</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nx">FormGroup</span><span class="p">;</span>
  <span class="nl">type</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nx">FormControl</span><span class="p">;</span>
  <span class="nl">price</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nx">FormControl</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="c1">// This is only here to make the form look more l3g1t</span>

  <span class="kd">constructor</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">private</span> <span class="nx">formBuilder</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nx">FormBuilder</span><span class="p">){</span>
    <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">form</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">formBuilder</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">group</span><span class="p">({</span>
      <span class="na">type</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="kc">null</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">Validators</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">required</span><span class="p">]],</span>
      <span class="na">price</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">Validators</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">required</span><span class="p">]]</span>
    <span class="p">});</span>

    <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="kd">type</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">form</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">controls</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="kd">type</span> <span class="k">as</span> <span class="nx">FormControl</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">price</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">form</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">controls</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">price</span> <span class="k">as</span> <span class="nx">FormControl</span><span class="p">;</span>
  <span class="p">}</span>
<span class="p">}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Then in our <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">property.html</code> template, we can utilize our Enum as follows.We will use the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">keyvalue</code> pipe.This takes our <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PropertyType</code> enum (referenced as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ePropertyType</code>) and turns it into a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">KeyValue</code> array, which we can iterate over with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*ngFor</code>.As we declared our <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PropertyType</code> with a string value(ie. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Apartment = 'Apartment'</code>) the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">KeyValue.key</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">KeyValue.value</code> will both contain the string value of the enum so we can use either.</p>

<p>We then can use our Enum as part of an <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*ngIf</code> to conditionally display a message.</p>
<div class="language-html highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nt">&lt;form</span> <span class="na">[formGroup]=</span><span class="s">"form"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
  <span class="c">&lt;!-- Property type form control --&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;label</span> <span class="na">for=</span><span class="s">"propertyType"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>Property Type<span class="nt">&lt;/label&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;select</span> <span class="na">id=</span><span class="s">"propertyType"</span> <span class="na">[formControl]=</span><span class="s">"type"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;option</span> <span class="na">[ngValue]=</span><span class="s">"null"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>Select one...<span class="nt">&lt;/option&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;option</span> <span class="na">*ngFor=</span><span class="s">"let type of ePropertyType | keyvalue"</span> <span class="na">[ngValue]=</span><span class="s">"type.value"</span><span class="nt">&gt;&lt;/option&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;/select&gt;</span>

  <span class="c">&lt;!-- Property price form control --&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;label</span> <span class="na">for=</span><span class="s">"propertyPrice"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>Property Price<span class="nt">&lt;/label&gt;</span>
  <span class="nt">&lt;input</span> <span class="na">id=</span><span class="s">"propertyPrice"</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"form-control"</span> <span class="na">type=</span><span class="s">"number"</span> <span class="na">[formControl]=</span><span class="s">"price"</span> <span class="na">placeholder=</span><span class="s">"Street..."</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>

<span class="nt">&lt;/form&gt;</span>

<span class="c">&lt;!-- Conditionally display a message if a certain PropertyType is selected (or not selected) --&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;ng-container</span> <span class="na">*ngIf=</span><span class="s">"type.value !== ePropertyType.House"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
Wouldn't you prefer a nice garden?
<span class="nt">&lt;/ng-container&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h1 id="how-to-get-an-array-of-strings-from-an-enum">How to get an array of strings from an Enum</h1>
<p>A nice little trick to get an array of strings <em>(<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">string[]</code>, or<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Array&lt;string&gt;</code> if you’re a cool boi like myself)</em> from an Enum is to use use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Object.keys</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Array.filter</code></p>

<div class="language-typescript highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c1">// Declare your enum</span>
<span class="kr">enum</span> <span class="nx">PropertyType</span> <span class="p">{</span>
  <span class="nx">House</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">House</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="nx">Apartment</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">Apartment</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="nx">Flat</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">Flat</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">,</span>
  <span class="nx">Studio</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">Studio</span><span class="dl">'</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="cm">/* Get an array of keys, filtering out number values
*  as the enum object itself is as follows
*  { 0: 'House', 1: 'Apartment' ...}
*/</span>
<span class="kd">const</span> <span class="nx">propertyType</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nb">Array</span><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="kr">string</span><span class="o">&gt;</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nb">Object</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">keys</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">PropertyType</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">filter</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">key</span> <span class="o">=&gt;</span> <span class="nb">isNaN</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="nx">key</span><span class="p">));</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h1>
<p>Enums are lit, use them more often.</p>]]></content><author><name>Shane McGowan</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="Angular" /><category term="TypeScript" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a short guide on using Enums in an Angular application. Below you will see how to: Reference an Enum in yourcomponent.html templates Itterate over an enum using *ngFor and the keyvalue pipe Conditionally show content using an Enum and*ngIf Get all the values of an enum as anArray&lt;sting&gt;]]></summary></entry></feed>